import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Which of the following characteristics is associated with insect-pollinated flower",
A: "They do not secrete nectar",
B: "The surface of the stigmas are sticky",
C: "Their flowers are inconspicuous",
D: "Their stamens have long filaments",
answer: "B. The surface of the stigmas are sticky",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The following materials are conductors of electricity except",
A: "blood",
B: "copper",
C: ". mica",
D: "water",
answer: "C. mica",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Acids react with many reactive metals to give off",
A: "hydrogen gas",
B: "oxygen gas",
C: "ammonia gas",
D: "carbon dioxide gas",
answer: "A. hydrogen gas",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The commonest for propagating crop in Ghana is by",
A: "budding",
B: "root cutting",
C: "seeds",
D: "stem cutting",
answer: "C. seeds",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Which device is used to measure the population density of a plant species",
A: "Pooter",
B: "Quadrat",
C: "Sweep net",
D: "Wire mesh",
answer: "B. Quadrat",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. The part of the eyes where images are formed is called",
A: "aqueous  humour",
B: "pupil",
C: "lens",
D: "retina",
answer: "D. retina",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The arrangement of electrons in a shells of an atom is called",
A: "atomic structure",
B: "periodic arrangement",
C: "electronic configuration",
D: "electronic structure",
answer: "C. electron configuration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. The type of soil erosion caused by water run-off from exposed land on a gentle slope is referred to as",
A: "gulley erosion",
B: "rill erosion",
C: "sheet erosion",
D: "splash erosion",
answer: "A. gulley erosion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. An advantage in the use of hard water is",
A: "furing kettle",
B: "blockage of water pipes",
C: "formation of scum",
D: "formation of strong bones",
answer: "D. formation of strong bones",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. In beta decay, the particle emitted is",
A: "electron",
B: "neutron",
C: "helium nucleus",
D: "hydrogen atom",
answer: "A. electron",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Introduction of a trivalent element into a tetravalent element \nI. is known as doping \nII. form an n-type semi conductors \nIII. forms a p-type semi conductor \nWhich of the  statement above is correct",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Which of the following animal is warm blooded",
A: "Agama lizard",
B: "Wall gecko",
C: "Cockroach",
D: "Mouse",
answer: "D. Mouse",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. In testing for starch in a green leaf, the leaf is boiled in ethanol so as to",
A: "kill the leaf cell",
B: "dissolved the chlorophyll",
C: "enable the iodine solution to penetrate the tissues",
D: "stop  all chemical reaction in the cell",
answer: "B. dissolve the chlorophyll",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The following statement are example of application of biotechnology in Agriculture except",
A: "crossing animals with desired characteristics",
B: "improving upon colour and size of a flower",
C: "introduction of foreign genes into livestock",
D: "development of pest- resistant crops",
answer: "B. improving upon colour and size of a flower",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Which of the following solvent could best use to remove ink stain in a dress",
A: "Ethanol",
B: "Kerosene",
C: "Milk",
D: "Petrol",
answer: "A. Ethanol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. A difference between an atom and a ion is that an atom",
A: "is electrically charged whilst a ion is neutral",
B: "has protons whilst a ion has no protons",
C: "can move about in solution whilsty a ion cannot move  in a solution",
D: "cannot conduct electricity whilst ions conduct electricity",
answer: "D. cannot conduct electricity whilst an ion conducts electricity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. The application of lime to soil is to",
A: "improve the toxicity of dissolved coper",
B: "improve soil structure",
C: "increase the availability of calcium ions",
D: "decrease the activity of soil living organism",
answer: "C. increase the availability of calcium ions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Which if the following food chain is correct",
A: "Grass – frog –grasshopper-hawk",
B: "Hawk –grass – grasshopper –frog",
C: "Grass – grasshopper – frog – hawk",
D: "Grasshopper –grass - frog – hawk",
answer: "C. Grass –> grasshopper –> frog –> hawk",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Which of the following traits in humans is an example of continuous variation",
A: "Gender",
B: "Colour blindness",
C: "Body mass",
D: "Blood group",
answer: "C. Body mass",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Which of the following metals will release hydrogen from dilute acids",
A: "Ag",
B: "Cu",
C: "Hg",
D: "Zn",
answer: "C. Hg",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. A property of a material that makes it a good conductor of heat is a",
A: "colour",
B: "length",
C: "nature",
D: "volume",
answer: "D. Universal indicator",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. The relative density of a substance has no  unit because it is",
A: "the ratio of mass to volume",
B: "a ratio of densities",
C: "always compared to  the density of water",
D: "a ratio of mass to density",
answer: "C. nature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Which of the following indicators could be used to determine a pH of a solution",
A: "Litmus paper",
B: "Methyl orange",
C: "Phenolphthalein",
D: "Universal indicator",
answer: "B. a ratio of densities",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. In fruits flies, the allele fro grey body colour is dominant and black body colour is recessive. Two grey- bodied flies mated and they produced 75 grey bodied flies and 25 black bodied flies. The cross described is most likely to be",
A: "GG ⅹ GG",
B: "GG ⅹ  gg",
C: "Gg ⅹ GG",
D: "Gg ⅹ Gg",
answer: "D. Gg x Gg",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Which of the following features areassociated  with dariy cattle? They  \nI. are lean with fairly long legs  \nII. have wedged shaped body conformation  \nIII. have welled developed udder  \nIV. are generally humped",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
D: "II, III and IV",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
instruction: "A girl of mass 60 kg runs a 100 m race in 10s.use the information to answer question 26 and 27.",
id: "question26",
question: "26. What is the speed of the girl",
A: "110 ms-1",
B: "100ms-1",
C: "50ms-1",
D: "10ms-1",
answer: "D. 10 ms-1",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. Calculate the kinetic energy of the girl",
A: "6000J",
B: "3000J",
C: "170J",
D: "40J",
answer: "B. 3000 J",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The atomic number of an  atom is 15 and its mass number is 32. Determine  the number of neutrons in the atoms",
A: "15",
B: "17",
C: "32",
D: "47",
answer: "B. 32",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. The IUPAC name of Na2SO4 is",
A: "sodium (II) sulphate",
B: "disodium sulphate",
C: "sodium tetraoxosulphate (IV)",
D: "sodium tetraoxosulphate (VI)",
answer: "D. sodium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Release of dust into the atmosphere  \nI. cut down photosynthesis \nII. cause respiratory disease \nIII. reduce visibility  \nWhich is the following  is correct",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Dehorning is important in animal production because is",
A: "control endoparasites",
B: "make it easy to handle animal",
C: "reduces the intake of food  of animal",
D: "makes easy identification of animal",
answer: "B. makes it easy to handle animals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Which of the following physical properties is associated to sandy soil  \nI. it is well aerated  \nII. it has apoor water holding capacity  \nIII. it is poorly drained",
A: "I and II",
B: "I and III",
C: "II and III",
D: "I,  II and III",
answer: "B. I and II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. What is the unit for momentum",
A: "kg m3",
B: "kg m s-1",
C: "kg m s-2",
D: "m s -1",
answer: "B. kg m s-1",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Which of the following statements about breathing in humans is correct?",
A: "The same amount of nitrogen, more carbon dioxide and less oxygen is breathed out than breathed in.",
B: "The same amount of nitrogen, less carbon dioxide and more oxygen is breathed out than breathed in.",
C: "More nitrogen, more carbon dioxide and less oxygen is breathed out than breathed in.",
D: "Same amount of nitrogen, more carbon dioxide and more oxygen is breathed in than is breathed out.",
answer: "A. The same amount of nitrogen, more carbon dioxide and less oxygen is breathed out than breathed in",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. An advantage of the use of hay over silage is that hay",
A: "ensures the availability of feed all year round.",
B: "has laxative effect.",
C: "has higher proportion of leaves, water and nutrients",
D: "is  more palatable to livestock",
answer: "A. ensure the availability of feed all year round",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The nuclide undergoes alpha decay, the mass number and the atomic number of the daughter nuclide are respectively",
A: "226, 89.",
B: "226, 88.",
C: "230, 90.",
D: "222, 86.",
answer: "D. 222, 86",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The concept of natural selection involves the following features except",
A: "survival of the fittest.",
B: "competition among organisms.",
C: "organisms with the best adapted features.",
D: "the use of the concept to classify organisms.",
answer: "D. the use of the concept to classify organisms",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. Refraction of light occurs because light travels from one medium to another",
A: "in the same direction.",
B: "with the same intensity.",
C: "with different velocities.",
D: "obeying the laws of reflection.",
answer: "C. with different velocities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Drug addiction is a brain disease because if",
A: "is chronic and relapsing.",
B: "is harmful and results in compulsive drug use",
C: "results in the structural change of the brain of the user.",
D: "makes the brain more sensitive to drugs",
answer: "B. is harmful and result in compulsive brain of the user",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. common disease that affects sheep is",
A: "anthrax.",
B: "aspergillosis.",
C: "coccidiosis.",
D: "gumboro.",
answer: "A. anthrax",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Which of the following gases are major atmospheric pollutants?  \nI.	Nitrogen dioxide \nII.	Oxygen \nIII.	Chlorofluorocarbon",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Ethanol may be preferred to mercury as a thermometric liquid because",
A: "ethanol is colourless.",
B: "mercury has a higher specific heat capacity.",
C: "mercury wets glass.",
D: "ethanol has a far lower freezing point.",
answer: "D. ethanol has a far lower freezing point",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following uses of substances is/are correct for esters? They are used as  \nI. solvents for quick-drying paints. \nII. flavours in food preparations and cosmetics. \nIII. drying agent in making textiles.",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and Il only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "C. I and II only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. In which of the following blood vessels is the pressure highest?",
A: "Hepatic artery",
B: "Renal artery",
C: "Dorsal aorta",
D: "Vena cava",
answer: "C. Dorsal aorta",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Yam is classified as a",
A: "cereal.",
B: "legume.",
C: ". root tuber.",
D: "stem tuber.",
answer: "C. root tuber",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. The Easterlies are winds, which blow",
A: "towards the poles.",
B: "from the poles to the equator.",
C: "along the equator.",
D: "into the sea.",
answer: "B. from the poles to the equator",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. An example of a saturated hydrocarbon is",
A: "ethane.",
B: "ethene",
C: "ethyne.",
D: "ethanol.",
answer: "A. ethane",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The structure in the human body which stores glycogen is",
A: "ileum.",
B: "liver.",
C: "lungs.",
D: "pancreas.",
answer: "B. liver",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. The image formed by a plane mirror is",
A: "magnified.",
B: "real.",
C: "laterally inverted.",
D: "diminished.",
answer: "C. laterally inverted",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. One disadvantage of mulching is that it",
A: "may be a source of new weed species.",
B: "acidifies the soil.",
C: "improves soil texture.",
D: "increases soil temperature.",
answer: "A. may be a source of new weed species",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]